This video shows how to set up sales tax
so you can be sure you're calculating
taxes correctly on transactions. We'll
see how to set up a tax group to assign
to items that you buy and sell to
indicate that you or your customer pay
sales tax on the
items. You'll learn how to set up tax
area codes that calculate sales tax on
sales and purchase documents based on a
customer or vendor and how to apply tax
area codes to customers and vendors
manually. These processes require
general ledger accounts for tracking
taxes on receivables and payables. Those
accounts are ready for us on the Ktoso
USA data set. We'll start by finding the
assisted setup guide on the business
manager role center. The guide creates a
tax group called taxable. We'll assign
this group to the taxable items that we
buy. Next, we'll specify the general
ledger accounts we'll use to track the
tax code for sales and the tax we're
paying for items we purchase. Sales
taxes are often a combination of city,
county, and state. We'll use the city of
Fargo with a rate of 2% in Cass County
and a state tax for North Dakota at 5%.
Business Central suggests the name Fargo
ND and we can change it as long as we
keep it unique. We're almost there. We
need to apply the tax area code to our
customers and vendors. The last step is
to make sure that this tax rate applies
only to the city of Fargo.
In the filter field, we'll choose city,
then fargo. We'll do that for customers
and vendors. That's all there is to it.
Now, when we create sales or purchasing
documents, Business Central calculate
sales tax based on the tax area codes
that we just assigned to customers and
vendors. The setup sales tax assisted
setup is a great way to quickly get
started. But what if we need to change
something? For example, if we add new
customers or buy from new vendors. What
if a jurisdiction's boundaries
change? Go to the customers or vendors
list. Now, choose the tax area code and
criteria to specify the businesses to
apply it
to. Thanks for watching this video about
how to automate sales tax calculations
for sales and purchase documents.